YAMADOU TRAORE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+221 77 259 70 19



yamadou21@gmail.com



Gibraltar III Villa 50, Dakar, Senegal



www.github.com/yamadou



Yamadou T.



SKILLS

Application Development

iOS Development

Tech Savvy

End-User Experience

Requirements Analysis

Software Implementation

Research and Development

Swift

Xcode

Backend

NodeJS

Express

EDUCATION

BS Candidate in Computer Science Seattle University, USA 2014 - 2016

AS in Computer Science Seattle Central College, USA 2013 - 2014

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A success-driven, creative, and analytic software developer with a comprehensive background in mobile and iOS application development, product development, and project management. A seasoned professional, leader, and team-builder offering well-rounded knowledge and experience in delivering client outcome-based application development solutions. A collaborative individual who works to seize upon emerging technological solutions to generate substantial and sustainable competitive advantages for clients. Possesses comprehensive experience in creating innovative and successful applications and the ability to increase the visibility and awareness of products.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Atos IOS Developer – <u>Lapose.net Mailing</u>

2021 - Present

- Outlined, programmed, and implemented an in-app review feature that dramatically improved app store ratings and reviews, thus increasing the number of reviews from 198 to 21,950 in 3 months.
- Utilized in-depth understanding of trends and strategies necessary to design the mailing app and collaborated with the team to develop and test the application, as well as oversee code releases,
- Analyzed the requirements and designed a technical approach toward releasing new features and ensured product stability after release; as a result, the rating went from 2.5 to 4.5 in three weeks.
- Oversaw application in production environment and provided real-time support for analyzing and troubleshooting issues.
- Initiated streamlining activities, including bug backlog for QMR reduction, process flow documentation, and testing resulting in enhanced application functionality.
- Researched various technologies useful for the project and kept in touch with the evolution of technology advancements and iOS policies, successfully updating the advertising and consent SDK.

Makeba Money IOS Developer – <u>Makeba Money</u>

2019 - 2021

- Acquired app information, remodeled the code for the money transfer and onboarding features, and assisted in architecture code refactoring of the whole app by transitioning from MVVM to Clean Architecture
- Facilitated the development of a suite of economic and easy-to-use mobile applications for financial transactions, including international remittances and local payments.
- Engaged in extensive research of financial market trends and performed needs analysis to bring integrated
 and cross-functional knowledge and skills set to the analysis provided to ensure continuous workflow of
 the mobile application.
- Delivered product expertise in the application development from requirements definition through successful deployment while working with all aspects of iOS development such as networking, data persistence, and UI development.

Team-X Group Software Developer

2017 - 2019

- Assessed existing processes and policies, documenting functional gaps to be addressed during the development and implementation of an innovative FinTech mobile application for the French startup Xaalys.
- Complied and analyzed competitive research to execute unique design concepts, developing accurate perceptions in a fast-paced, tight deadline environment.
- Exhibited proficiency in working with XCode and Swift to build the V1.0 of the iOS app from initial conception to the final delivery; single-handedly coded and designed over 100 screens
- Applied technical expertise to develop a NoSQL database (MongoDB), RESTAPI (Nodejs), and frontend (Angular), and provided RESTful web service development through NodeJS.
- Strengthened the startup identity by integrating the Banking as a Service (BAAS) <u>Treezor</u>, while providing critical product consultation and technical expertise to ensure a successful implementation.
- Championed the complete spectrum of product development and project management, resulting in better collaboration with the team to drive the full application life cycle, spanning ideation and design implementation.
- Successfully handled most problems, decisions, and escalations and utilize analytical skills to find a path forward in difficult situations.